Sometimes you just want to preview your Parquet file without writing a script.
I'm going to show you how easy it is to do in Positron.
Just drag and drop your Parquet file into the File Explorer, and the Data Explorer immediately
opens up in the workspace.
At a glance, it shows you the column names, data types, distribution of values, summary
statistics, and percent missing.
And it also shows a spreadsheet-like view of the contents, where you can temporarily
sort and filter for quick information gathering.
If you want to make those changes permanent, it provides a SQL syntax to add it to your
code.
And from there, you can dive into the rest of your analysis in Positron.
Do you work with Parquet files often?
What would make your life easier?
Let us know in the comments.